[
  {
    "question": "Q. Who is the head of the church? Prove from scripture.",
    "answer": "A. Jesus Christ (Col 1:18)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What is the constitution of the Presbyterian Church in America?",
    "answer": "A. The Westminster Confession of Faith, together with the Larger and Shorter Catechism, and the Book of Church Order."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What are the marks of the church? Prove from scripture.",
    "answer": "A. The preaching of the Word (2 Tim 4:1-2), administration of the sacraments (1 Cor 11), and church discipline (Matt 16 & 18)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Define three basic forms of church government.",
    "answer": "A. Episcopalian church government consists of a hierarchy of priests and bishops who have final authority in the government of the church.<br>Presbyterian church government affirms the importance of the 'connectional' nature of the church; that is, that each local congregation is 'connected' both doctrinally and in practice to other local congregations via presbyteries and the General Assembly. Each local church is governed by a session, each session is accountable to a presbytery, and every presbytery accountable to the General Assembly.<br>A Congregational church government views each local church as autonomous and self-governing, and sees no place for any official, governmental connection between local churches."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Why are you Presbyterian? What are its strengths? What is the Biblical argument for it?",
    "answer": "A. I believe it to be the most biblical form of church government and the wisest practically. Christ is head of the church, and we possess no single seat of power to exercise ultimate authority, and the structure is means to protect both church members and officers. We find Scriptural examples of church leadership by elders in Acts 14 and Titus 1, shared authoirty and connectionalism in the Jerusalem council of Acts 15, plurality of elders in Acts 20 and 1 Peter 5, with Christ as the head of the church (Matt. 18; Eph. 4), and the right of the congregation to elect those whom God has called (Acts 6)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Who are the members of Presbytery?",
    "answer": "A. Teaching elders and churches within its bounds that have been accepted by the Presbytery."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Who can join the local church?",
    "answer": "A. Those who have made a profession of faith in Christ, been baptized, and admitted by the Session to the Lord's Table"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What authority does the church possess?",
    "answer": "A. The authority of the church is ministerial and declarative. It has the authority to retain and remit sins (WCF 30.2)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Define church discipline. What is the purpose of church censures?",
    "answer": "A. The exercise of the authority given to the church to promote its purity and welfare. For the reclaiming and restoration of the offending brethren, deterring similar offences, purging that which might corrupt the whole, vindicating the honor of Christ, and preventing the wrath of God (WCF 30.3)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What censures may the church impose?",
    "answer": "A. Admonition, suspension from the Lord’s Supper for a season, and excommunication from the church (WCF 30.4)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What are the principles of Presbyterian church government?",
    "answer": "A. Christ is the head of His church & the source of all its authority; Christ exercises His authority through the Word and His Spirit.<br>Christ has endowed His church with authority—with specific authority to its officers.<br>Each local church is ruled by a session, comprised of teaching and ruling elders called by Christ and recognized by the members of the church as their leaders.<br>Each local church is represented by chosen members of its session within a presbytery, a church court comprised of teaching and ruling elders from each church within a certain geographical area.<br>The denomination as a whole is represented in the General Assembly, which serves as the highest court of the church."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Who are the officers of the Church, according to Scripture?",
    "answer": "A. Teaching elders, ruling elders and deacons (1-4)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Compare and contrast the office (orders) of teaching elder and ruling elder. What is meant by the parity of elders?",
    "answer": "A. Parity is that each elder, regardless of TE or RE, has the same joint power. One office, equal in authority, distinction in function and gifts. TEs are those set apart to the ministry of Word and sacrament. REs are those from the congregation, called by God and elected by the congregation as their representatives and shepherds. Both are called to the shared work of overseeing and shepherding God’s flock."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Contrast the “joint power” of the Session and the “individual power” of an elder?",
    "answer": "A. Joint power is the exercise of the elder’s authority and power within context of the session as a body. The elder individually does not make binding decisions on behalf of the other elders, but is to shepherd, pray for, visit, and instruct members."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. In the New Testament what is the relationship between elder and bishop?",
    "answer": "A. Term is used of the same office. Bishop describing the exercise of oversight and elder the work of shepherding, being an example to the flock and governing well."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What do we mean by “submission to the brethren”?  How is it relevant in the context of a Session decision with which you may disagree?",
    "answer": "A. It is the obligation of obedience to ecclesiastical authority. In the instance of a session decision, it means being respectful and yielding personal opinions to the collective decision of the body."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. How are ruling elders and deacons elected?",
    "answer": "A. Congregation submits names; a time of training is held; Session examines those whose names have been nominated and trained, and then submits those approved to a congregational meeting; congregation elects by a majority vote (24-1, 3)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What the duties of a deacon? To whome are the deacons accountable?",
    "answer": "A. To help those in need; to encourage stewardship in the members of the church; to collect and to distribute the gifts of the people; to care for the property of the church, both real and personal (9-2). They are accountable to the Session."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Who can approve a church budget?",
    "answer": "A. The Session."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Who can approve a call a pastor?",
    "answer": "A. The congregation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Who can buy property?",
    "answer": "A. The congregation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Who can elect a church treasure?",
    "answer": "A. The diaconate."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What are the 5 permanent committees of the General Assembly?",
    "answer": "A. Administrative Committee (AC), CDM, MNA, MTW, RUF (Program Committees)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What are the 5 agencies of the PCA?",
    "answer": "A. Covenant College, Covenant Theological Seminary, Geneva Benefits, PCA Foundation, Ridge Haven Conference Center"
  }
]
